[Music]
the following is a production of Frankie
Freitas and the internet Museum of
hologography
[Music]
hello everyone this is Frankie Freitas
and welcome to another week of whole
talk for the week of April 5th 1999 my
guest this week is Alan Rohde from Ross
books and Alan is going to come on the
show to tell listeners about the release
of their eighth edition of the
holography marketplace which is the
reference guide for those working in the
field of Photography and those who also
need to get more information about those
working in the field of holography
what's special about this eighth edition
is that it contains a full color
photopolymer hologram on its cover
manufactured by dynapon in Japan
and this is the first publication in the
world to have a color hologram on its on
its cover
and it makes it basically a collector's
item for this eighth edition
the holography marketplace is uh quite a
bit more than just a listing of who is
working in the field of holography
contained within its cover you can also
find information on what Holograms are
Holograms are made the different types
of holograms and how they differ from
one another the different types of
lasers that are used to make Holograms
and a lot of other technical information
also
also especially for this issue a lot of
technical information on the new
emulsions such as those from
BV plates from Germany and slavage
materials a lot of technical
specifications on those as well so it's
really a working guide for a lot of
people that are working in the field of
holography as well it's a very valuable
tool for the art world for art directors
and different people who are working in
the creative Fields who someday may have
to and
applications or specify a job that will
contain a hologram and it gives them a
lot of background information so they
can make Intelligent Decisions and
intelligent choices as to
what a hologram is capable of doing and
also what it's not capable of doing and
it gets them and right in the ball game
very quickly so it's a great publication
I look forward to receiving it all the
time and I think I may even be one of
the first people to call because I know
as soon as I get the announcement in the
mail
I walk right over to the phone and call
and order my copy and I can read that
copy from cover to cover
we're going to take a break from the
laser diode
and laser pointer holography reports
this week
but next week I'd like to get back on
track with that in this studio here in
my studio downtown Pennsylvania we were
able to make a hologram using one of the
higher power diodes the higher power
being relatively speaking compared to
the laser pointers we used a 15
milliwatt 635 nanometer semiconductor
diode to create a hologram here it was a
very good test I do have some photos and
some information up on the web already
so if you go to my laser pointer part of
my website you'll be able to see the
latest report on using this diode and
this is very exciting because it's
moving us into higher powers
I'm looking forward to continuing to do
experiments to see how high we can go
can we go up into the 30 milliwatt range
can we go into the half Watt 500
milliwatt range and have very high power
diodes creating Holograms so we'll get
back on that next week and we'll
concentrate on the
the interview with Alan Rhody this week
so I'm not going to come back on after
the interview is over so I will say
thank you for tuning in now and I hope
you tune in each and every week to
hollow talk and to get news and
information and guests and interviews
before the field of lasers and
holography
and um
after this message we will be right back
the interview with Alan Rhody from Lost
Books thanks for tuning in see you next
week
would you like to make your own
one-of-a-kind hologram and learn how you
can start making holograms on your own
at the same time you can do this and
much more by attending one of Frankie
greatest's holography workshops from
beginner to Advanced Frank's got a
workshop that's just right for you from
single afternoon evening or weekend
introductory workshops to Wednesday
evening five-week complete courses and
don't forget his newest Workshop laser
pointer holography
located just off the Northeast Extension
of the Pennsylvania Turnpike and
Interstate 78 the studio is a quick
non-stop drive from the New York
Philadelphia and Baltimore Washington DC
areas for more information call the
Studio's toll-free hotline at
1-800-458-3525 and begin your own
Journey with holography today that's
1-800-458-3525 for more information on
attending a Frankie Freitas holography
Workshop today
foreign
it's Frankie Freitas how are you hi
Frank I'm just fine I gave you a call so
that the holotalk listeners can get an
update on your latest
holography Marketplace fantastic and
it's that time again it's always a
welcome sight to see the holography
marketplace arrive in the mail thank you
we got a good one this year oh you
certainly do want to why don't we start
off with probably the biggest news of
course that's for you to decide what the
biggest news or not but the biggest news
to me was that cover the cover hologram
uh represents I think the first True
caller which is full color uh
mass-produced hologram that is produced
on photopolymer a very practical plastic
material and practical to use and
it was produced by Guy Nippon uh the
printing company in Japan on a Dupont
material Dupont photopolymer uh they
call it a true color material because
every color can be replicated
realistically in the samples they sent
us originally they had blacks they had
whites
full colors that hard colors reproduce
like brown
so it's pretty remarkable technology
they're the first ones really to put it
out and I was surprised to see the whole
process explained right in the
marketplace itself yeah pretty much most
of it we got in touch with the guys that
actually make them they um has been
working with Dupont over 10 years
because dagnet Bond also makes involved
Holograms and they've had a good working
relationship but they were the first
company really to put together the
lasers the replicator other people have
made full color Holograms other people
have experimented with them a little on
the full color material but this is
first
commercial mass production
they did a job of trading cards in Japan
some Astro Boyd trading cards they sent
us some samples that were relatively
large compared to all the other
photopolymer samples out there it was a
five inch by seven inch scene and we cut
it in half for the cover of the book of
parrots in the jungle and you can see
the parrots have you know red blue green
yellow
they're sitting on Brown branches and
the image appears to be about three
three inches deep yeah it nice and clear
it's nice and bright it's viewable and a
wide variety of lighting conditions yeah
good lighting you know it appears the
best but it has a lot of commercial
applications I found that the image
actually exceeds the thickness of the
book yeah
right through the book now for listeners
who may be logging on that may not be
familiar with the photography
Marketplace we wanted to just take a few
moments to explain in general what it is
and what it's about Roth books started
publishing holography related materials
back in 1982 when they brought out the
holography handbook and there wasn't
much of a holography industry back then
what existed was really the retail
Marketplace for holographic art and gift
commercially it started being used a lot
in the mid 80s when manufacturers
figured out how to hot stamp one type of
hologram embossed foils onto paper and
cardboard so the industry developed and
we started tracking industry in 1989
with a book called The holography
Marketplace which is a business
directory that's updated regularly and
text and reference material and then
what makes it look extra unique is the
manufacturers put Holograms in the book
so
it acts like a sample kit for people
that either collect Holograms or want to
see what the manufacturers have to offer
what's available to them to actually
purchase some people might look at the
book say yeah I want a hologram like on
page 17. other people no I like this
kind that's on page you know 27. yeah uh
so the book is now coming out annually
it's about 250 Pages
22.95 ship it anywhere in the world
for additional you know UPS or Postal
charge and it's got 20 Holograms in it
this year each year we feature a new
state-of-the-art hologram on the cover
that represents what's either coming
right out of the research Labs or
available in the top manufacturers you
couldn't buy those holograms for 20
probably just one of those Holograms
would cost more than 22 minutes yeah the
one on the cover this year you know in
the uh if it was available that was
invented you know way back when it'd
probably be about a 70
dollar hologram yeah matted and framed
up which we encourage people to do by
two and keep one on the bookshelf hey
I've been thinking about that yourself
yeah it's going to be a real Collective
item because it's analogous to the first
color photograph yeah that salad and you
know I'm sure in 10 years these will be
common plays and there are a couple
companies in the United States you know
working with Dupont to start production
uh since the stuff is so rare and only a
few people can do it the natural
commercial application security because
anytime only one Factory can make
something it makes it you know hey hard
to copy so in Dupont and a couple
manufacturers one use this material for
security purposes but at least the
Japanese and one or two other companies
are either doing you know ongoing
research or trying to start commercial
this display applications uh signage or
maybe replicating artwork or in this
case doing everything from trading cards
to
you know at point of purchase displays
premiums that sort of thing yeah so
right now there's really only one plant
in commercial production in the world
and that is a dynapon of Japan now if
you're listening to the show I want you
to grab a pencil and paper because I'm
going to ask Alan in just a few moments
to give the contact information on
ordering your own copy of Photography
Marketplace so you might want to reach
into the desk or wherever you happen to
have your pencil and paper stored and
get that and get that ready so you can
write this down and we'll also have a
link right to the Ross books website now
if you're listening to this and you
think that you're an amateur or hobby
slowgrapher or something like that and
then you're not really interested in
what other companies are working with
holography the holography marketplace is
actually a whole lot more than that from
what I was able to sit down and read so
far and I do read every issue of these
from cover to cover even the listings
every page
you have a lot of information in there
on what Holograms are how lasers work I
mean it's almost like an instruction
guide right well yes because it's meant
to it's primarily meant for the
intelligent business person that wants
to use holography but might only know
what he's heard in the movies so it
starts off very basic every chapter
starts off very basic we break it into
the basics an introduction to holography
you know what it's all about how you can
use them how many of them are around in
the world today and then if you want to
make them yourself you know the basic
theory behind them and then as the
chapters go on it gets more in depth of
materials and the lasers and
Commercial applications but each chapter
you know we actually intended
consciously to start
anybody can understand it yeah a couple
formulas and things are thrown in at the
end for the people that need that too
yeah I found it very valuable to have a
comprehensive in the world of technical
specifications for the new emulsions
which are really hard to find right the
guys that are making holograms on a
day-to-day basis will appreciate the
book and then again for the person
that's just starting out or just the
artist uh the designer who's never going
to make a hologram but might have to
design one or their company you know
president comes in the door hey what's
what's going on how can we use these
they have to come up with some answers
they might not actually be in the lab
making them but we have to give them
some information they can use too a lot
of polygons now being made with video
footage and computer footage and Digital
Data that people have around
and
um this there's a chapter that says how
you can integrate that and make a longer
amount of that yeah it's probably really
important for art directors and people
who are working on the creative end of
it to understand what this process is
like I get emails all the time a few
weeks ago I got an email from a guy
asking would it be possible to make a
holographic parade float
and how the would it be able to be used
in the daytime or could the street
lights illuminate the parade float as it
came down the street and that is right
yeah it would be great but it's a wild
idea I mean we're not gonna we're not
going to see any holographic Parade
floats coming down the street
a book like this I don't know about 10
o'clock tonight
a book like this would give artists art
directors and some of the other people
working in uh Production Studios an
opportunity to see what holography is
capable of doing and also what it's not
capable of doing because it's not
capable of doing a lot of the things
that people think that it can absolutely
and we have that in a chapter too
we actually do have an article in there
this year a couple about the myths of
holography written by a guy that makes
holograms for displaying exhibition
every day so but yeah there's some good
information in there are the listings up
or down as far as people working in the
field of Photography things are up it's
spreading out well we're also reaching
um many more people through the internet
so it's probably a combination of
there's more businesses more specialized
businesses and we're just hitting uh a
lot of people that we couldn't several
years ago on you know because it was
just fax machines yeah and now you know
we can put out an internet search and uh
we get emails every day from all across
the world you can send the book out all
over the world yeah
how about if you give people information
on how they can order the holography
marketplace from you and like I said we
also have a link to your website if they
can order it also from the web exactly
yeah um the easiest way to get a hold of
us uh since you're at your computer and
email uh we're at sales rossbooks.com
and uh by phone you can get a hold of us
if you're in the U.S 1-800-367-0930
International is 510-841
and the old-fashioned fax machine
510-841-2695
and our address is rossbooks or
separate workbooks
P.O box 4340 Berkeley
California
your first your first issue of this
is a collector's item now 500 bucks yeah
uh we didn't realize that there's a
there's a book collector's Market but
they don't really even care that it's a
holography book but since it can never
be reprinted because these Holograms
will never be made again it's very
valuable in that there is a it's a
limited edition yeah and now the book
collectors are learning all about
holography yeah so uh yeah keep them all
we're actually selling the back editions
too for a very nice price and uh but to
college one day often yeah it's also a
great historical record of holography in
the field as well those collections
exactly yeah exactly there's some
Pioneers in there well Alan I want to
thank you for being a guest and taking
the time to come on a few minutes to
talk with us about this latest eighth
edition of the photography Marketplace
and uh wish you good luck with it this
time around just as you've had in the
past with the other editions as well my
pleasure last thing I want to say is
just keep visiting that holy world
website thank you that's a great one
okay
okay bye-bye